American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIe. 1845-1865 APS.Archives.IIe APS.Archives.IIe
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to George Ord, April 15, 1847; 7 3/8" x 9 1/4"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. Acknowledges receipt of box of A. P. S. Transactions by the Saranak.
  - Letter to A. Langdon Elwyn, Philadelphia, April 16, 1847; 10x8; Harvard University
    Cambridge, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Edward Everett, Pres. and Thaddeus William Harris, Librarian. 1p.,end.by J.F.F[isher] and add. Thanks for Transactions.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, April 17, 1847; 9x7; Royal Asiatic Society of Great Britain and Ireland
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: R.Clarke. 1p.,end.: J.F.F. Thanks for Transactions and Proceedings
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 20, 1847; 10-3/4x8-3/4; Kongelige Danske videnskabernes selskab
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., April 20, 1847; 8 3/8" x 10 5/8"; Royal society of sciences of Copenhagen.
    [Copenhagen], 1 p. and endorsement. L.S.: H. Orsted. Forwards designated publications to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, April 24, 1847; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Königlich Bayerische Akademie der Wissenschaften
    Munich, Printed L.filled in in ms. 1p.,end. In German. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 27, 1847; 9-1/2x8; Royal Geographical Society (Great Britain)
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: William Humble. 1p.,end.: R.D[unglison]. Thanks for Transactions.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, April 29, 1847; 14x9; Geological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Wm.J. Hamilton. 1p.,end.: J.F.F.[isher], and add. Thanks for Transactions and Proceedings
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April, 1847; 9-3/4x8; Zoological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Wm.Ogilby. 1p.,end.: C.B.T[rego]. Thanks for Proceedings and Transactions
  - Letter to R[obley] Dunglison, May 1, 1847; 9-3/4x8; Bowditch Library
    Boston, A.L.S.: H.I.Bowditch. 1p.,end.and add. Thanks for Transactions of APS.
  - Report of committee on paper by Prof. Norton "On the imponderable agents of nature", May 7, 1847; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia] D.S.: Joseph Henry, R. M. Patterson and Rich[ar]d S. McCulloch. 1p. See APS Proc., IV, 332.
  - Letter to George Ord, May 11, 1847; 7 3/8" x 8 3/4"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. Is sending designated journals to the A.P.S. by the Monongehela.
  - Letter to George Ord, May 18, 1847; 7 5/16" x 8 15/16"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. Encloses his account up to the present time, for £2.3.2.
  - Account with George Ord, May 18-Nov. 3, 1847; 7-1/2x9; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
  - Letter to George Ord, May 21, 1847; 6 7/16" x 8 1/4"; Tidyman, Philip
    Charleston, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Prevented from visiting Philadelphia by illness. Encloses $5 subscription to the A.P.S. Cold winds have injured the cotton crop in South Carolina and Georgia.
  - Letter to A[lfred] L. Elwyn, Philadelphia, May 24, 1847; 10x8; Harvard University
    Cambridge, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Edward Everett, Pres.and Thaddeus William Harris, Librarian. 1p.,end.by J.F.F[isher] and add. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to Robley Dunglison, May 24, 1847; 10-3/4x8-1/4; New York State Library
    Albany, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: T.Romeyn Beck. 2p.,end.: J.F.F[isher]. Thanks for Proceedings and asks for missing parts of Transactions.
  - Letter to Robley Dunglison, Philadelphia, June 4, 1847; 9-3/4x8; Bowditch Library
    Boston, A.L.S.: H.I.Bowditch. 1p.,end.and add. Thanks for Proceedings and other favors from the APS.
  - Letter to George Ord, June 11, 1847; 7 3/16" x 8 15/16"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
  - Letter to [George] Ord, June 19, 1847; 6 1/8" x 7 15/16"; Wood, George B. (George Bacon), 1797-1879
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. A.N. in 3d. per. Presents to the A.P.S. a two volume set entitled, Practice of Medicine.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Ord, June 24, [1847]; 4" x 6 1/4"; Du Bois, William E. (William Ewing), 1810-1881
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Wishes to borrow a Low Dutch and English dictionary from the A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 1/13, 1847; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Moskovskoe obshchestvo li︠u︡biteleĭ prirody
    Moscow, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Renard. 1 p.,end.: C.B.T[rego] and end. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to George Ord, July 8, 1847; 7 5/8" x 9 11/16"; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
    Librarian of the A.P.S., Washington, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Regarding $65, standing to the credit of the A.P.S. on the books of the treasury of the United States.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., July 13, 1847; 7 3/4" x 9 1/2"; Palfrey, John Gorham, 1796-1881
    Secretary's Office, Boston, 1 p. and endorsement. L.S. Offers a copy of map of Massachusetts for acceptance by the A.P.S.
  - Letter to George Ord, July 15, 1847; 7 15/16" x 10"; Peale, Titian Ramsay, 1799-1885
    Treasurer of the A.P.S., 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Encloses draft for $65, drawn from the treasury of the United States, payable to the order of the A.P.S.
  - Report of committee on W[illiam] MCIlvaine's supplement to his "Perpetual calendar", July 16, 1847; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia] D.S. John F. Frazer and R. M. Patterson. 1p. See APS Proceedings, IV, 344.
  - Letter to G[eorge] Ord, July 16, 1847; 7 15/16" x 9 7/8"; Kane, John K. (John Kintzing), 1795-1858
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. A.L.S. Encloses a letter concerning Mr. Lewis (missing), which he requests be referred to a committee of the A.P.S.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., July 24, 1847; 7 15/16" x 9 7/8"; Osgood and Company
    New York, 2 pp., address and endorsement. L.S. Offers the columns of The Literary World to a notice of the proceedings of the A.P.S.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, July 26, 1847; 11x8-1/2; Deutsche Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin
    Berlin, Printed L. filled in in ms. S.: J.F.Encke. 1p., end. In German. Thanks for Transactions and Proceedings.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Ord, West Chester, July 26, 1847; 7 9/16" x 9 3/4"; Darlington, William, 1782-1863
    1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Thanks Mr. ord for permission to examine dried plants received from Professor Savi of the University of Pisa. Thinks they should be sent to A[sa] Gray at Harvard.
  - Letter to W.[sic] A[lfred] Langdon Elwyn, Philadelphia, July 28, 1847; 10x8; Harvard University
    Cambridge, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Edward Everett, Pres. and Thaddeus William Harris, Librarian. 1p.,end.: J.F.F[isher], and add. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to John F. Frazer, August 3, 1847; 4 13/16" x 7 5/8"; Tilghman, Richard Albert, 1824-1899
    London, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests Mr. Frazer to present a communication of his to the A.P.S. See Pro., IV, 345.
  - Letter to George Ord, August 11, 1847; 7 9/16" x 9 3/4"; Darlington, William, 1782-1863
    West Chester, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Recommends that entire collection of plants received from Professor Savi be forwarded to Dr. [Asa] Gray at Harvard. Presents a copy of Agricultural Botany to A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to [John F.] Frazer, August 13, 1847; 8 1/16" x 10 1/8"; Reed, Henry, 1808-1854
    Bordentown, N. J., 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Will prepare an obituary notice of the late James G. Thomson for the A.P.S. See Pro., IV, 345.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., August 15, 1847; 7 3/4" x 12 7/8"; Königlich Preussische Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin
    Berlin, 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: J. F. Encke. (In German.) Presents to the A.P.S.: Transactions, 1845; and Monthly Reports, July, 1846- June, 1847.
  - Letter to George Ord, August 18, 1847; 7 9/16" x 9 3/4"; Darlington, William, 1782-1863
    Librarian of A.P.S., West Chester, 3 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Concerning the origin of the potato and the sweet potato. Proposes A[sa] Gray for membership in the A.P.S. Not found May, 2011.
  - Letter to George Ord, August 18, 1847; 4 9/16" x 7 1/2"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 2 pp. and endorsement. L.S. Acknowledges receipt of letters of July 30 and June 12, 1847. Thinks great fall in price of grain will cause many bills to be protested.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Ord, Philadelphia, Aug. 24, 1847; 10-3/4x8-1/2; Bataviaasche genootschap von kunsten en wetenschappen
    Amsterdam, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: W.Vrolik. 1p.,end.and add. In French. Thanks for Transactions and Proceedings
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., August 25, 1847; 7 1/2" x 9 3/4"; Eichthal, Gustave d', 1804-1886
    Paris, 1 p. and endorsement. L.S. (In French.) Ethnological Society of Paris sends certain of its publications to the A.P.S.; requests an exchange of publications.
  - Letter to G[eorge] Ord, L-10, September 6, 1847; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Holbrook, John Edwards, 1794-1871
    Librarian of A.P.S., New York, 1 p. address and endorsement. A.L.S. Regarding presentation of a set of his North American Herpetology to the A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Sept. 8, 1847; 10-3/4x8-1/2; Académie royale des sciences, des lettres et des beaux-arts de Belgique
    Brussels, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Quetelet. 1p.,end. In French. Thanks for Proceedings and Transactions
  - Letter to George Ord, September 10, 1847; 9 1/4" x 7 3/8"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. Is sending designated journals to the A.P.S. library by the Monongehela. Encloses a parcel for [John James] Audubon.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., September 16, 1847; 8 5/16" x 10 5/8"; Moskovskoe obshchestvo li︠u︡biteleĭ prirody
    Moscow, 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: Dr. Renard. (In French.) Sends to the A.P.S.: Bulletin, no. 2, 1847.
  - Report, Sept. 17, 1847; 7x8; American Philosophical Society. Committee on finance
    [Philadelphia] D.S.: Clement C. Biddle, R. M. Patterson and Isaac Lea. 1p.
  - Report of committee on claim of William D. Lewis against the APS, Sept. 17, 1847; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia] D.S.: J. K. Kane, Clement C. Biddle and N. Chapman. 1p. and end.
  - Report of committee on paper by Richard A. Tilghman, "On the decomposing power of water", Sept. 17, 1847; 9x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia] D.S.: John F. Frazer, R. M. Patterson and Franklin Bache. 1p. and end. See APS Proc., IV, 353-355. Printed: APS Trans., n.s., X, 173-176.
  - Letter to the Corresponding Secretary of the [American] Philosophical Society, October 1, 1847; 6 3/4" x 8 3/8"; Shulz, Theodore
    Salem, N. C., 2 PP., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Introducing the Rev. N. O. Tank, and requesting for him the use of Arawak manuscripts in the library of the A.P.S.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the [American] Philosophical Society, October 4, 1847; 7 5/16" x 8 15/16"; Bancroft, George, 1800-1891
    U.S. Legation, London, 1 p., address and endorsements. Sends to the A.P.S.: a copy of Sir J. F. W. Herschel's "new work" (not named).
  - Letter to George Ord, October 9, 1847; 7 3/8" x 8 7/8"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. Is sending designated journals to the A.P.S. library by the Susquehanna.
  - Letter to George Ord, October 18, 1847; 4 1/2" x 7 1/2"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 2 pp. and endorsement. L.S. Concerning Professor [Heinrich Christian] Schumacher's accounts.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, October 22, 1847; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Gilliss, J. M. (James Melville), 1811-1865
    Washington, 1 p. A.L.S. in 3d. per. Submits correspondence with Dr. Gerling on new method of finding solar parallax. Asks that A.P.S. promote proposed expedition to the island of Chiloe.
  - Letter to R[obert] M. Patterson, October 27, 1847; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    South Berwick, Me., 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Encloses memorial of Lieut. [J. M.] Gilliss to the A.P.S., upon a new method of determining the solar parallax. Cf. Minutes, Nov. 5, 1847, in Pro., IV, 361.
  - Letter to G[eorge] Ord, October 28, 1847; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Dunlap, James D. (James Darwin), 1809-1858
    Treasurer of A.P.S., Philadelphia, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Encloses letter from Charles E. Sherman regarding claim of A.P.S. for $65, which dwindled to 65 cents.
  - Letter to the President of the A.P.S., November 1, 1847; 8 3/4" x 11"; Académie royale des sciences de Stockholm
    Stockholm, 1 p. and endorsement. D.S. (In French.) Presents publications listed herein to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to George Ord, November 3, 1847; 7 3/8" x 9 1/16"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Encloses account for £4.0.2 due him. Parliament to meet on the 18th, to try their hand at amending commercial and colonial affairs.
  - Letter to George Ord, November 9, 1847; 8 1/2" x 11"; Alexander, Stephen, 1806-1883
    Princeton, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Encloses amount due on account of Astronomische Nachrichten. Has delivered message to Professor [Joseph] Henry. FILM 235 FRAME 41
  - Letter to Rob[er]t M. Patterson, November 10, 1847; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Gilliss, J. M. (James Melville), 1811-1865
    Washington, 3 pp. A.L.S. Upon the need of government support for expedition to southern hemisphere to determine the solar parallax.
  - Letter to George Ord, November 11, 1847; 7 3/8" x 9 1/4"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
  - Letter to F.S. Astaburuaga, November 14, 1847; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Gilliss, J. M. (James Melville), 1811-1865
    Washington, 2pp. A.L.S. Copy. Requests the Chilian secretary of legation for meteorological data upon the southern part of Chili. Enclosed in: Gilliss to R.M. Patterson, December 11, 1847.[In seperate folder: Dec. 11,1847]
  - Letter to G[eorge] Ord, Nov. 17, 1847; 12x8; McClure, John
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Estimate of repairs and alterations for Philosophical Hall. See APS report of Nov. 19, 1847.
  - Letter to George Ord, Novermber 19, 1847; 7 5/8" x 9 13/16"; Lewis, William D.
    Treasurer of A.P.S., [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Concerning his claim against the A.P.S.
  - Report of special committee on Philosophical Hall, Nov. 19, 1847; 12x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia] D.S.: G. Ord, Geo. W. Smith and J. J. Van der Kemp. 2p. Possibility of renting rooms to city. See also letter from McClure to George Ord; Nov. 17, 1847.
  - Permit to George Ord to land parcel from overseas, Nov. 21, 1847; 8x7; Pennsylvania. Board of Wardens for the Port of Philadelphia
    D.S.: S.C.U. Hopkins, D'y Collector, and J. G. George, D'y Naval Officer. 1p.and end.
  - Letter to J. M. Gilliss, November 26, 1847; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Astaburuaga, Francisco Solano, 1817-1892
    Washington, 2 pp. Copy of L. Information concerning rainfall in southern Chili. Enclosed in: Gilliss to R.M. Patterson, December 11, 1847.
  - Letter to George Ord, November 27, 1847; 8" x 10"; Harris, Thomas
    Washington, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests bill for amount of dues owed by him to the A.P.S.
  - Report of special committee on Philosophical Hall, Nov. 30, 1847; 12x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia] D.S.: G. Ord, J. J. Van der Kemp, and Geo. W. Smith. 1p., end. Advises acceptance of offer by city to rent north room.
  - Letter to George Ord, December 1, 1847; 8" x 10"; Harris, Thomas
    Washington, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of bill for his dues. Will pay it "the last of this month."
  - Letter to George Ord, Librarian of the A.P.S., December 2, 1847; 8 3/8" x 10 5/8"; Ombrosi, James
    Florence, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. The U. S. consul at Florence announces the death of Count Jacob Graberg de Hemsö. See Pro., V, 5.
  - Report of committee on letter from William D. Lewis making. a claim against the APS, Dec. 3, 1847; 10x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia] D.S.: J.K. Kane and Clement C. Biddle. 2p. and end.
  - Letter to George Ord, Leeds, December 3, 1847; 4 1/2" x 7 1/8"; Denny, Henry, 1803-1871
    1 p. and endorsements. A.L.S. Sends to the A.P.S.: Proceedings of the Geological and Polytechnic Society of Yorkshire.
  - Letter to George Ord, December 10, 1847; 7 1/4" x 9 1/8"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. Is sending designated journals to the A.P.S. library by the Saranak.
  - Letter to R[obert] M. Patterson, December 11, 1847; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Gilliss, J. M. (James Melville), 1811-1865
    President of the A.P.S., Washington, 1 p. A.L.S. Regrets not having furnished the A.P.S. with sufficiently detailed information upon the climate of southern Chili.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., December 14, 1847; 5" x 8"; Smyth, C. Piazzi (Charles Piazzi), 1819-1900
    Edinburgh, 1 p. and endorsements. A.L.S. Royal Observatory presents Astronomical Observations, VII, to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to G[eorge] Ord, December 16, 1847; 8 1/4" x 10 9/16"; Phillips, Jonas, and Company
    Librarian of the A.P.S., New York, 1p., address and endorsement. N.S. Acknowledges receipt of two boxes to be forwarded to Leghorn; "We have put the same on board of the Brig Trio ... "
  - Letter to George Ord, December 17, 1847; 7 1/4" x 9 1/8"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. Acknowledges receipt of draft for £4.0.2. Establishment of semi-monthly mails during the winter and weekly mails during the summer.
  - Report of special committee on Philosophical Hall, Jan. 7, 1848; 12x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia] D.S.: G. Ord, Geo. W. Smith and J. J. Van der Kemp. 1p., end. Refusal of city to rent north room.
  - Report of committee on communication by J. M. Gillis regarding dimensions of the solar system, Jan. 7, 1848; 10x7; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia] D.S.: R. M. Patterson, R. S. McCulloch and E. O. Kendall. 3p. and end. See APS Proc., V, 3.
  - Letter to the Librarian of the A.P.S., January 11, 1848; 7 3/8" x 8 7/8"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. Is sending designated journals to the A.P.S. library by the Philadelphia packet.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., January 15, 1848; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Jones, Milton A.
    U.S. brig Perry, Buenos Ayres, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests copies of certain issues of A.P.S. Proceedings, for Don Pedro de Angelis.
  - Report of committee on Prof. Bache's letter relative to U.S. coast survey, Jan. 19, 1848; 12-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia] D.S.: R. M. Patterson, John F. Frazer, E. Otis Kendall and J. K. Kane. 14p. and end.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Jan. 31, 1848; 10x7-3/4; Königlich Bayerische Akademie der Wissenschaften
    Munich, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Freyberg. 2p.,end,: R.D[unglison]. In French. Thanks for Proceedings and Transactions Forwards publications.
  - Letter to George Ord, February 1, 1848; 8" x 10"; Short, Charles Wilkins, 1794-1863
    Louisville, Ky., 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests copies of certain issues of A.P.S. Proceedings, in order to complete his set.
  - Letter to the Librarian of the A.P.S., February 11, 1848; 7 3/8" x 8 7/8"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 8, 1848; 10-1/2x8-1/4; American Antiquarian Society
    Worcester, A.L.S.: Sam[ue]l F. Haven, Libn. 1p., end. Thanks for Transactions.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, March 8, 1848; 10x7-3/4; Bowditch Library
    Boston, A.L.S.: H. I. Bowditch. 1p.,end.: J.F. F[isher],and add. Thanks for Transactions and Proceedings
  - Letter to Charles B. Trego, March 10, 1848; 7 3/8" x 8 7/8"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    Librarian of A.P.S., London, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. Is sending designated journals to the A.P.S. library by the Wyoming.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 16, 1848; 10-3/4x8-1/4; New York State Library
    Albany, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: T.Romeyn Beck. 1p.,end. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to John K. Kane, Philadelphia, March 25, June 13, 1848; 10x8; Harvard University
    Cambridge, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Edward Everett, Pres. and Thaddesu William Harris, Librarian. 1p.,end.: C.B.T[rego], and add.,end. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to Nathaniel Chapman, April 4, 1848; 6 1/4" x 8"; Moore, Jacob Bailey, 1797-1853
    New York, 1 p. and endorsements. A.L.S. Sends to the A.P.S.: Bulletin of Proceedings of the New York Historical Society.
  - Letter to George Ord, April 7, 1848; 7 3/8" x 9 1/4"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 2 pp., address and endorsement. L.S. Acknowledges receipt of letters of January 26 and 27, 1848. Mentions outbreak of revolutions in Europe.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, April 11, 1848; 8-3/4x5-1/2; New Jersey Historical Society
    Newark, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: W.A.Whitehead, end.: C.B.T[rego] and add. Thanks for Transactions.
  - Letter to Robert M. Patterson, April 13, 1848; 7 7/8" x 10"; Dickerson, Mahlon, 1770-1853
    Suckasunny, N. J., 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Encloses check for $20, to cover "five or six years" receipt of A.P.S. Proceedings. see Pro., V, 19.
  - Letter to G[eorge] Ord, April 16, 1848; 5 3/8" x 8"; Squier, E. G. (Ephraim George), 1821-1888
    Corresponding Secretary of the A.P.S., New York, 1p. and endorsements. A.L.S. Sends to the A.P.S.: memoir upon Aboriginal Monuments of the Mississippi Valley.
  - Letter to Ch[arle]s B. Trego, April 19, 1848; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Dickerson, Mahlon, 1770-1853
    Secretary of A.P.S., Suckasunny, N.J., 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests that the 34th. number of A.P.S. Proceedings be sent to him.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 2, 1848; 9x7-1/2; Royal Institution of Great Britain
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: John Barlow 1p.,end.: C.B.T[rego]. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to C[harles] B. Trego, May 9, 1848; 7 3/8" x 8 15/16"; Rolandi, Pietro, 1801-1863
    Secretary of A.P.S., London, 1p., address and endorsement. L. Lack of information from Lloyds leaves but little doubt that the brig Trio has foundered. Information communicated to Dr. Labus.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s B. Trego, May 12, 1848; 7 3/8" x 8 7/8"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. Is sending designated journals to the A.P.S. library by the Tuscarora.
  - Letter to John F. Frazer, May 16, 1848; 7 11/16" x 9 3/4"; Gilliss, J. M. (James Melville), 1811-1865
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Washington, 3 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of diploma of membership in A.P.S. Announces the death of Dr. Nürnberger. See Pro., V, 24.
  - Letter to the Librarian of the A.P.S., June 5, 1848; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Alexander, Stephen, 1806-1883
    Princeton, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests that Mr. Gibson be allowed to examine the Philosophical Transactions for May, 1841.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, June 10, 1848; 7 5/8" x 9 3/4"; Society for the Development of the Mineral Resources of the United States
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. Pr.D.S.: P. A. Browne, President; M. W. Dickison, Corr. Sec. Announcing the formation of the society.
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s R.[sic] Trego, June 10, 1848; 7 3/8" x 8 7/8"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850